{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The minimum recommended diameter of sewers, is", "opta": "5 cm", "optb": "10 cm", "optc": "15 cm", "optd": "20 cm.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Aerobic bacterias", "opta": "flourish in the presence of free oxygen", "optb": "consume organic matter as their food", "optc": "oxidise organic matter in sewage", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rate of accumulation of sludge in septic tanks is recommended as", "opta": "30 litres/person/year", "optb": "25 litres/person/year", "optc": "30 litres/person/month", "optd": "25 litres/person/month.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If 2% solution of a sewage sample is incubated for 5 days at 20\u00b0C and depletion of oxygen was found to be 5 ppm, B.O.D. of the sewage is", "opta": "200 ppm", "optb": "225 ppm", "optc": "250 ppm", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If D is the diameter of upper circular portion, the overall depth of a standard egg shaped section, is", "opta": "D", "optb": "1.25 D", "optc": "1.5 D", "optd": "1.75 D", "opte": "2 D.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the diameter of sewer is 225 mm, the gradient required for generating self cleansing velocity, is", "opta": "1 in 60", "optb": "1 in 100", "optc": "1 in 120", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following :", "opta": "pH value indicates acidity and alkalinity of sewage", "optb": "In acidic sewage, the pH value is less than 7", "optc": "In alkaline sewage, the pH value is more than 7", "optd": "Fresh sewage is generally alkaline", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The non-clog pump which permits solid matter to pass out with the liquid sewage, is", "opta": "centrifugal pump", "optb": "reciprocating pump", "optc": "pneumatic ejector", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Assertion (A) : Discharging the effluents from the oxidation ponds just up stream of lakes or reservoirs is undesirable. Reason (R) : The discharged algae get settled in the reservoirs and cause anaerobic decomposition and other water qualities.", "opta": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation of A", "optb": "Both A and R are true but R is not a correct explanation of A", "optc": "A is true but R is false", "optd": "A is false but R is true.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The width of a rectangular sewer is twice its depth while discharging 1.5 m/sec. The width of the sewer is", "opta": "0.68 m", "optb": "0.88 m", "optc": "1.36 m", "optd": "1.76 m.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following :", "opta": "In treated sewage, 4 PPm of D.O. is essential", "optb": "Only very fresh sewage contains some dissolved oxygen", "optc": "The solubility of oxygen in sewage is 95% that is in distilled water", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In olden days the type of section adopted in trunk and out fall sewers was", "opta": "parabolic shaped", "optb": "horse shoe shaped", "optc": "egg shaped", "optd": "circular shaped.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the survival of fish in a river stream, the minimum dissolved oxygen is prescribed", "opta": "3 PPm", "optb": "4 PPm", "optc": "5 PPm", "optd": "10 ppm.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a fully mechanised composting plant, involves", "opta": "mechanized receipt", "optb": "mechanized segregation", "optc": "mechanized pulverising of refuse", "optd": "all of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Self-cleansing velocity is", "opta": "velocity at dry weather flow", "optb": "velocity of water at flushing", "optc": "velocity at which no accumulation remains in the drains", "optd": "velocity of water in a pressure filter.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the over land flow from the critical point to the drain is 8 km and the difference in level is 12.4 m, the inlet time is", "opta": "2 hours", "optb": "3 hours", "optc": "4 hours", "optd": "5 hours.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An inverted siphon is designed generally for", "opta": "one pipe", "optb": "two pipes", "optc": "three pipes", "optd": "four pipes.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A rainfall may be classified as acidic if its pH value is less or equal to", "opta": "6", "optb": "7", "optc": "5", "optd": "6.5", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When drainage to sewage ratio is 20, the peak dry weather flow is", "opta": "20% of the design discharge", "optb": "slightly less than 5% of the design discharge", "optc": "slightly more than 5% of the design discharge", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For treating the sewage of a large city, you will recommend", "opta": "a sedimentation tank and an activated sludge treatment plant", "optb": "a plant consisting of Imhoff tanks with low rate trickling filters", "optc": "sedimentation tanks with high rate trickling filters", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The detention time of a circular tank of diameter d and water depth H, for receiving the sewage Q per hour, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The dimensions of a rectangular settling tank are : length 24 m, width 6 m and depth 3 m. If 2 hour detention period for tanks is recommended, the rate of flow of sewage per hour, is", "opta": "204 cu m", "optb": "208 cu m", "optc": "212 cu m", "optd": "216 cu m", "opte": "220 cu m.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The screens are fixed", "opta": "perpendicular to the direction of flow", "optb": "parallel to the direction of flow", "optc": "at an angle 30\u00b0 to 60\u00b0 to the direction of flow", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In primary sedimentation, the 0.2 mm inorganic solids get separated if specific gravity is", "opta": "2.25", "optb": "2.50", "optc": "2.55", "optd": "2.65", "opte": "2.75", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the in-correct statement from the following :", "opta": "Manholes are provided in sewer pipes at suitable intervals", "optb": "Catch basins are generally provided in sewers for carrying drainage discharge", "optc": "Inlets are generally provided in all sewers", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Clogging of sewers, is caused due to", "opta": "silting", "optb": "low discharge", "optc": "greasy and oily matters", "optd": "domestic wastes thrown in manholes", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A sewer pipe contains 1 mm sand particles of specific gravity 2.65 and 5 mm organic particles of specific gravity 1.2, the minimum velocity required for removing the sewerage, is", "opta": "0.30 m/sec", "optb": "0.35 m/sec", "optc": "0.40 m/sec", "optd": "0.45 m/sec", "opte": "0.50 m/sec.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The coagulant widely used for sewage treatment, is", "opta": "alum", "optb": "ferric chloride", "optc": "ferric sulphate", "optd": "chlorinated copperas.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "House connections to the laterals is generally made by", "opta": "R.C.C.", "optb": "P.C.C.", "optc": "Cast iron", "optd": "Glazed stonewares.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ratio of maximum sewage flow to average sewage flow for mains up to 1 m in diameter, is", "opta": "1.5", "optb": "2.0", "optc": "3.0", "optd": "4.0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dilution method of disposing off sewage, is not preferred to", "opta": "when sewage is fresh", "optb": "when diluting water has high dissolved oxygen content", "optc": "when diluting water is used for water supply near the point of sewage disposed", "optd": "when the diluting water is having flow currents", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For house drainage minimum gradient is", "opta": "1 in 60", "optb": "1 in 80", "optc": "1 in 10", "optd": "1 in 400", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the side of a square sewer is 1000 mm, the diameter of a hydraulically equivalent circular section, is", "opta": "1045 mm", "optb": "1065 mm", "optc": "1075 mm", "optd": "1095 mm.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ratio of minimum hourly flow to the average flow of sewage is", "opta": "1/4", "optb": "1/3", "optc": "1/2", "optd": "3/4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bio-chemical oxygen demand (BOD) for the first 20 days in generally referred to", "opta": "initial demand", "optb": "first stage demand", "optc": "carbonaceous demand", "optd": "all of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Flocculated particles do not change their", "opta": "size", "optb": "shape", "optc": "weight", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For non-scouring velocity 5 m/sec, the type of sewers generally preferred to, is", "opta": "cast iron sewers", "optb": "cement concrete sewers", "optc": "glazed bricks sewers", "optd": "stone ware sewers.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Disposal to sewage in large cities, is done in", "opta": "irrigation", "optb": "dilution", "optc": "oxidation", "optd": "putrifaction.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the COD test of sewage, organic matter is oxidised by K2Cr207 in the presence of", "opta": "H2SO4", "optb": "HNO3", "optc": "HCl", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In R.C. sewer pipes, the percentage longitudinal reinforcement to the cross-sectional area of concrete is kept", "opta": "10.0", "optb": "5.0", "optc": "2.0", "optd": "0.25", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The asbestos cement pipes are generally laid", "opta": "horizontally", "optb": "vertically", "optc": "at an angle of 30\u00b0", "optd": "at an angle of 60\u00b0.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chlorination of water is done for the removal of", "opta": "bacterias", "optb": "suspended solids", "optc": "sediments", "optd": "hardness.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For evaporation and measurement of settlable solids, the apparatus used, is", "opta": "a jar", "optb": "a breaker", "optc": "a test tube", "optd": "an Imhoff cone.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In SI units the power of sound is represented in", "opta": "kgs", "optb": "joules", "optc": "neutons", "optd": "watts.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A rain sanitary sewer is constructed to carry", "opta": "sanitary sewage", "optb": "storm sewage", "optc": "surface water", "optd": "ground water", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sewage is pumped up", "opta": "from low lying areas", "optb": "from flat areas", "optc": "from basements", "optd": "across a high ridge", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Removal of oil and grease from sewage, is known", "opta": "screening", "optb": "skimming", "optc": "filtration", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The gas which may cause explosion in sewers, is", "opta": "carbondioxide", "optb": "methane", "optc": "ammonia", "optd": "carbon monoxide.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In sewers the effect of scouring is more on", "opta": "top side", "optb": "bottom side", "optc": "horizontal side", "optd": "all sides.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}